(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-01T09:47:59.543350",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
このあと、ラプラスさんの生誕祭があるらしいんですけどー
Apparently, Laplus's birthday live is coming up after this, but...
（ラプラスの生誕祭は）割とレベルの高い合格点を越える生誕祭をオールウェイズ出してくれる
Laplus's birthday lives always exceed a high standard of quality.
どこから来たんですか？
Where did you come from?
えーと、スト6の方から
Um, from Street Fighter 6.
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
開会してんでしょ？
It's opening, right?
閉会してます！
It's already closed!
開会してんでしょ？
It's opening, right?
閉会してます！
It's already closed!
さっき開会してるって言ったじゃん
You just said it was opening!
閉会してます！
It's already closed!
ラプラス・ダークネスの生誕祭は…閉会しています！
Laplus Darknesss's birthday live is... closed!
みんな！我が輩の誕生日ライブにきてくれてありがとねー！
Everyone! Thank you so much for coming to my birthday live!
まずは1曲目！夜行性ハイズ！
First song! Nightwalker's Haze!
いくぞー！
Let's go!
カタツムリたい 忘れてたい
I want to be a snail, I want to forget
そんな顔で いつまで戦うの また一人で
How long will you keep fighting with that face, all alone again?
愛しても 明日ても
Even if I love you, even if tomorrow,
そのたびに傷口が顔を出す 巻き戻すように
every time the wound shows its face, like it's rewinding.
どうして 1から10まで
Why, from 1 to 10,
さらに100まで飲み込む 悲しみだけは
and even up to 100, only the sorrow I swallow
片付けたい
I want to tidy up,
忘れてたい
I want to forget.
そんな顔でいつまで戦うの また一人で
How long will you keep fighting all alone again?
愛しても 愛しても
No matter how much I love you,
その度に傷口が顔を出す 巻き戻すように
the wounds surface every time, just like rewinding.
どうして1から10まで 飲み込む悲しみだけは
Why is it that the sorrow never fades away?
総じて逃げ場もないのに -100から始まる動悸の日々も
Even with nowhere to run, the days of palpitations start from -100,
隠してくれないや
and you won't let me hide.
ちゃんと泣いて無理もしたら
If I cry properly and push myself too far,
ここへおいでよ いつだって
then come here anytime.
これからを沸かせようか
Shall we make the future boil?
眠たいが寝ない
I'm sleepy but I can't sleep,
まだ今日が良い
I still want today to be good.
僕ら何度だって想い合って光っていくんだよ
We will love each other again and again and shine.
消せない最低は理想じゃない
This unerasable worst is not the ideal.
なんかハイなシャイがちょうどいいや 救いたいのさ
A bit high and a bit shy is just right to save you.
死にたい 消したい も異常じゃない
"I want to die" or "I want to disappear" is not abnormal either.
よしよしのシークレットミーティングにほら吐き出しちゃおう
In a secret meeting, let's spit it all out.
君は泣いたって綺麗だよ
Even if you cry, you're beautiful.
さらばアンチビート 前を向いて笑っていこうじゃないもう
Goodbye, anti-beat, let's face forward and smile already.
寂しくない 悲しくない
It's not lonely, it's not sad.
塗り重ねた強がり 深い青 洗い流せたら
If I wash away the layers of bluffing...
バイバイを バイバイを
Then say bye-bye, say bye-bye.
バカみたいな世界にありがとう 探さないでね
Thank you to this stupid world, please don't look for me.
そして僕らは広くも狭くも
And then we will, in this room that is neither wide nor narrow,
熱くも寒くもない
neither hot nor cold,
この部屋で抱き合って息をするの
hug each other and breathe.
常識はずれを外して
If we break the common sense
二人だけの愛言葉で鍵をかけたら
and lock the door with our own secret love language,
さあどんな夜行をしようか
then what kind of night shall we make?
だけど痛い だから痛い
But it hurts, so it hurts,
優しさが染み込んでいく
and the gentleness soaks into the wounds.
将来を始めようか
Shall we start the future?
眠たいが寝ない
I'm sleepy, but I won't sleep,
まだ今日が良い
I still want today to be good.
僕ら何度だって想い合って光っていくんだよ
We will love each other again and again and shine.
消せない最低は理想じゃない
This unerasable worst is not the ideal.
なんかハイなシャイがちょうどいいや 救いたいのさ
A bit high and a bit shy is just right to save you.
死にたい 消したい も異常じゃない
"I want to die" or "I want to disappear" is not abnormal either.
よしよしのシークレットミーティングにほら吐き出しちゃおう
In a secret meeting, let's spit it all out.
君は泣いたって綺麗だよ
Even if you cry, you're beautiful.
さらばアンチビート 前を向いて笑っていこうじゃないもう
Goodbye, anti-beat, let's face forward and smile already.
寂しくない 悲しくない
It's not lonely, it's not sad.
塗り重ねた強がり 深い青 洗い流せたら
If I wash away the layers of bluffing...
バイバイを バイバイを
Then say bye-bye, say bye-bye.
バカみたいな世界にありがとう 探さないでね
Thank you to this stupid world, please don't look for me.
えっとね まだまだ続くから めっちゃ楽しんでってね
It's still going, so keep enjoying it!
バイバイ バイバイ バイバイ バイバイ
Bye-bye, bye-bye, bye-bye...
東京・渋谷 20時すぎ
[Title: Tokyo Shibuya 20:00 past]
今回、ラプラスさんの生誕祭があるらしいんですけど、
I heard La+ Darknesss has her birthday stream today...
えっ、マジですか？
Wait, really?
あの、え、ラプラスさんって、あのホロライブの？
La+ Darknesss from Hololive?
僕、あのーあれ、待ち受けにしてるんですよ。
I actually have her as my phone wallpaper.
しかも今回の話すトークが、ラプラスバースデイ2025らしくて、
And the talk show is supposed to be La+ Birthday 2025...
えー！マジでショックです。
Seriously, I'm shocked.
でも、幸せならOKです。
But if she's happy, it's okay!
ねえあたしのことが好きなら 気づいて
Hey, if you love me, please notice.
夢を見させてよ
Let me dream.
どうしてわかってくれないの？
Why can't you understand?
嫌いだ 二度と触れないで
I hate you, never touch me again.
ちょっと待って
Hey, wait a second.
ねえあたしのことが好きなら 気づいて 夢を見させてよ
Hey, if you love me, please notice, let me dream.
どうしてわかってくれないの？
Why can't you understand?
嫌いだ 二度と触れないで
I hate you, never touch me again.
ちょっと待って どこからおかしくなったの
Wait a second, when did things start going wrong?
ダメなとこも好きになれて よかったのに
I loved the bad parts too, everything was fine.
ぱーっと飲んで 誰かに埋めてもらえたら
Only if I could drink a lot and have someone fill this hole,
あなたのこと忘えられると 思っていた
I thought I could forget about you.
“トモダチ”ってさ 都合よくない？
"Friend" is so convenient for you, don't you think?
けど繋がってるなら悪くはないね
But if we are still connected, I guess it's not that bad.
騙し騙し生きて病んじゃってさ
I was living a lie and started feeling down.
優しくされると余計にツライ
It's even worse when you are nice to me.
ねえあたしのことが好きなら 気づいて 夢を見させてよ
Hey, if you love me, please notice, let me dream.
どうしてわかってくれないの？
Why can't you understand?
嫌いだ 二度と触れないで
I hate you, never touch me again.
呪ってあげるわ
I'll put a curse on you
ねえ あたしからの返事だよ
Hey, this is my reply to you
ウソつき ウソつき ウソつき ウソつき
Liars, liars, liars, liars
でもあなたが好きなの
Even so, I love you
吸って吐いて そうちゃんと言いって
Breathe in, breathe out, live properly
粗末な愛の子だとか しつこく急かすようだ
Like some crude, unrequited love child, nagging persistently
ねえ置いてかないで ねえお腹空いた
Hey, don't leave me behind. Hey, I'm hungry
見て見ぬふりツバを吐いて 燃えないゴミにするんだ
Turning a blind eye, spitting, turning me into unburnable trash
ねえあたしのことが好きなら
Hey, if you love me,
気づいて気づいて気づいて気づいて 夢を見せてよ
Notice me, notice me, notice me, notice me, show me a dream
どうして戦ってくれないの
Why won't you fight back?
嫌いだ嫌いだ嫌いだ嫌いだ
I hate you, I hate you, I hate you, I hate you
大嫌いだもうあなたは救えないの
I despise you, you can't be saved anymore
気づいてる 気づいてる
You've noticed, you've noticed
気づいてる 気づいてる 口に私は
You've noticed, you've noticed, to my mouth...
どうして全く変われないの
Why can't you change at all?
知りたいよ知りたいよ知りたいよ知りたいよ離れたくないよ
I want to know... I don't want to part ways
生まれたのはいちにのさんで
Born at the count of one, two, three
流れ星あのことのこと祝ってあげるわ
Shooting star, I'll celebrate that person's existence
ねえ最後にキスをさせてほし
Hey, let me have a kiss at the very end
ありがとう ありがとう ありがとう ありがとう これであなたも
Thank you, with this, you too...
次のラプラスさんの曲、アンドロイドがあるらしいんですけど
I heard Laplus's next song is called "Android," but...
え、何すか？
Huh? What is that?
それは許せないと思います、これ。
I think that's unforgivable, honestly.
「テメぇらバカかよ！」というのが第一ですね
My first thought is, "Are you guys stupid?!"
ラプラスといえば、“アイドル”みたいなものですからね
Speaking of Laplus, she's basically an "idol," right?
それはちょっとね… まあ世上は許してくれませんよ
That's a bit... Well, society won't forgive that.
おいおい一緒に作ろうよ
Hey hey, let's make it together
君とマッチアップの勝手
Matching up with you as we please
甘えても足りないの
Even if you spoil me, it's not enough
鍛え思い出染み出したシドのスタイル
The refined style born from our memories
変わる変わる傷つけては持ち帰って
Changing, changing, hurting each other and taking it back home
嘘出ないから折り紙つきのダマし合い
A certified game of deception, since it's not a lie
目を見ればすぐにわかるって馬鹿みたい
How foolish to think I'd understand just by looking in your eyes
妄想で作っていうほど
So much so that it's made of delusions
この愛は腐ってるんだよ
This love is already rotting away
早く気づいてくれよ
Hurry up and realize it
アンドロイドガールおかしくなっちゃった
Android Girl, you've gone crazy
僕だけのものになった君は誰なの
Who are you, now that you've become entirely mine?
ずっと ずっと信じてきたのにさ
Even though I've believed in you all this time
アンドロイドガール思い出なんだっけ
Android Girl, what was that memory again?
君とのキスが絶賛息を閉じたの
Our kiss triumphantly took my breath away
ずっと ずっと何の愛を最新更新したって
No matter how much I update and renew our love,
ちょっとだって変われぬと知らないよ
You don't know that nothing can change even a little bit
ああ可愛いねどうしてくれるよ
Ah, you're so cute, what are you going to do about this?
もう疲れたドキドキさせるセジのサイズ
I'm already tired of the thrilling sizes
不在不在の並行剤の
Of the absent, parallel remedies
期待しているのかわからなくなったよ
I've grown unsure if I'm even expecting anything anymore
アンドロイドはまだだってどこにいても一緒だな
Androids are still the same no matter where you are
ってマジで言いたい歌唱に浸っていたから
Because I was soaking in a song where I seriously wanted to say that
あの子の願っていたから
Because that child was wishing for it
早く何か教えてよ
Hurry up and tell me something
アンドロイドガールおかしくなっちゃった
Android Girl, you've gone crazy
君だけのものになった僕が好きなの
Do you like that I've become entirely yours?
ずっと ずっとダマして来たんだね
You've been deceiving me all this time, haven't you?
アンドロイドガール思い出したって
Even if I remember, Android Girl
錆びついた腕でんだ僕を求めて
Seeking me with your rusted arms
ずっと ずっと何の愛を再起動したって
No matter how many times I rebooted our love,
ちょっとだって変われぬと知らないよ
You don't know that nothing can change even a little bit
アンドロイドガールおかしくなっちゃった
Android Girl, you've gone crazy
僕だけのものになった君は誰なの
Who are you, now that you've become entirely mine?
ずっと ずっと信じてきたのにさ
Even though I've believed in you all this time
アンドロイドガール思い出なんだっけ
Android Girl, what was that memory again?
君とのキスが絶賛息を閉じたの
Our kiss triumphantly took my breath away
ずっと ずっとお邪魔から離れない君だけは許さない
I will never forgive you for clinging and never leaving me alone
アンドロイドガールおかしくなっちゃった
Android Girl, you've gone crazy
もういっそ“一緒ランド”作りましょ
We might as well just create our "Togetherland"
君とマッチアップ 乗っかって
Hopping on this match-up with you
「構ってても 足りないの」
"Gimme me more attention. It's not enough."
歌え 想い出浸り出す嫉妬のStyle
Sing it—the style of jealousy steeped in memories.
代わる代わる傷付けては
We took our turns to hurt each other
「もうしない」って嘘で仲直りごっこだ
lying about how we "won't do it anymore."
勘違いの騙し合い
We both cheat on each other with misunderstandings
目を見ればすぐに分かるってバカみたい
"You can tell by looking in their eyes"—how stupid is that?
この愛は腐ってるんだよ 早く気付いてくれよ
This love has so rotted away, just realize it already!
Android Girl おかしくなっちまった 僕だけのものになった
Android Girl, I've gone mad, you've become mine and mine alone
君は“誰”なのだろう? ずっと
but "who" exactly are you? All this time,
ずっと信じてきたのにさ
all this time I believed in you.
Android Girl 思い出はなんだっけ 君とのキスが痛くて 息を閉じたの ずっと ずっと
Android Girl, what was that memory? The kiss with you hurt so much, I stopped breathing, always, always...
何度愛を再起動したって ちょっとだって変われやしないよ
No matter how many times I reboot love, not a single thing changes.
ホロライブ 影が薄い ラプラス・ダークネス
[Title: Hololive's Faint Shadow: La+ Darknesss]
ホロライブでラプラスさんの影が薄いというお話なんですが
They say your shadow is pretty faint in Hololive, La+.
いや、納得できないね
No, I can't accept that.
Q ラプラスさんの魅力は?
Q: What is La+ Darknesss's charm?
ないんだな、それが
There isn't any, actually.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 作詞・作曲:kemu
[Title: Dear Doppelganger / Music by kemu]
どうも こんにちは きみのぶんしん です
Hello there, I'm your doppelgänger.
なんの じょうだん か めを こすってみる
What kind of joke is this? I rub my eyes.
かげ が ふたつ のびて そして またまく は あがる
Two shadows stretch out and the curtain rises once again.
もう ひとりぶん が いたら と あなた は いました
"If only there was another me," you said.
そんな しんしな ねがい が ぼく を よんだの さ
"That earnest wish of yours is what summoned me."
それや ねがった とも
I certainly wished for it,
かなんしんく すべて の エージェント
through all the hardships and bitterness, all of the agents.
かてい は いいから けっか を ください
Forget the process, just give me the result.
むいみ で むいな だいしょう
A meaningless and pointless price to pay.
ねえ こんな こと より
Hey, there's something more important than this,
だいじな こと が あるんだよ いいだろ ええ やります やります
isn't there? Yes, I'll do it, I'll do it,
なんでも やります
I'll do anything.
ぼく は きみ の ぶんしん です ふくみわらい で メサイア は いう
I am your doppelgänger, the messiah says with a smirk.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー きみ は きみ は だれ
Dear Doppelgänger, who are you?
呪詛 こんどう と こうさして ぼく は だれ
Ah, mixing and intersecting, who am I?
ねえ ありもしない 0 と 1
Hey, there's no proof anywhere for the non-existent 0 and 1.
しょうめい の こんげん なんて どこ にも
Dear Doppelgänger, who is who?
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー だれ は だれ は きみ
むしばまれた そんざい に せかい は きづかない ね
The world doesn't notice this eroded existence.
なりやまなみ さめどまない きせき の りんね が
The miracle's cycle, that never stops ringing, never stops awakening,
くるった せいかい を そめあげて るんぱっぱ
colors the warped correct answer, run-pappa.
どうも おかしい げつようび
Hello there, something's weird about this Monday.
ひとつ ふたつ と くずれてく じつざい が
One by one, the inconsistencies crumbling away
ぼく を かいりする
make me suspicious of myself.
おまえ は いったい だれ だ と
"Who the hell are you?"
ちょっと まって
Hold on a second.
しらない きのう しりもしない ことば
A yesterday I don't know, words I've never heard.
そうやって いつまにか やらかげ は とけてゆく
Just like that, before I knew it, my shadow melts away.
ぼく は なになんだろ
What on earth am I?
ねえ どうか そのざい を かえして
Hey, please, give me back my existence.
あいだ の くさむし だ が こっち は こっち で ずいぶん ここち が よく て
"Unfortunately for you, over here, it's quite comfortable."
もう あなた の いばしょ は どこ にも ない こと わかってる ん でしょ
"You know you don't have a place here anymore, don't you?"
ねえ うばわれた なら うばえば いい だろ こんど は おまえ の ばんだ から
"Hey, if you got robbed, just rob back, because next time, it'll be your turn."
ふくみわらい で インベーダー は いう
The invader says with a smirk:
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー きみ は きみ は だれ
Dear Doppelgänger, who are you?
呪詛 こんどう と こうさして ぼく は だれ
Ah, mixing and intersecting, who am I?
まあ それは そう か そう だよ な
Well, I guess that's just how it is.
いのち の いす は ひとつ だけ
There's only one chair for life.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー だれ は だれ は きみ
Dear Doppelgänger, who is who?
こぼれ おちた ひとつぶ かわきhatete まえ に
Before the single fallen drop dries up,
dare demo ii nani demo ii utsuwa o kudasai
Anyone will do, anything will do, please give me a vessel.
くるった せいかい を そめあげて るんぱっぱ
The warped correct answer colors everything, run-pappa.
Pray それは ずっと つづく ひともごう の れんさ
Pray / It's a chain of human karma that lasts forever.
Pain ゆだねあって ゆるしあって みたされ ゆく
Pain / Entrusting to each other, forgiving each other, being fulfilled.
Pray かけた ピース むこうの ペインきぼう また あい も
Pray / The missing piece, the worthless pain, hope and love too.
Pain たくしあって うまれかわる イニシエーション
Pain / Entrusting to each other, being reborn, initiation.
Pray ぼくのほうが ちゃんと きみ を いきてやる から
Pray / "Because I'll live your life properly for you."
Pain きみも つぎの だれか ちゃんと すくわなくちゃ
Pain / "You have to save the next person, too."
Pray もう わかってんだろ なにを すれば いいか さ
Pray / "You already know what you have to do, don't you?"
Pain どうか だれか ぼく に きせき を くれよ
Pain / Please, someone, give me a miracle.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー きみ は きみ は だれ
Dear Doppelgänger, who are you?
呪詛 コンドウ と こうさして ぼく は だれ
Ah, mixing and intersecting, who am I?
もう とまらない もどれない
It won't stop anymore, I can't go back.
どうも こんにちは きみの
Hello there, your...
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー それは それは ぼく
Dear Doppelgänger, that is... that is me.
むしばまれた そんざい に せかい は きづこう が
Even if the world notices this eroded existence,
もう なりやまなみ さめどまない きせき の りんね が
the miracle's cycle, that never stops ringing, never stops awakening,
くるった せいかい を そめあげる
will color the warped correct answer.
ううまく やれよ るんぱっぱ
Do it well, run-pappa.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー きみ は きみ は だれ
Dear Doppelgänger, who are you?
呪詛 コンドウ と こうさして ぼく は だれ
Ah, mixing and intersecting, who am I?
もう とまらない もどれない とうも こんにちは きみの
It won't stop anymore, I can't go back. Hello there, your...
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー それは それは ぼく
Dear Doppelgänger, that is... that is me.
むしばまれた そんざい に せっかい が きづこう が もう なりやまなみ さめどまない
Even if the world notices this eroded existence, it never stops ringing, never stops awakening,
きせき の りんね が くるった せいかい を とめあげる
the miracle's cycle will stop the warped correct answer.
さあ うまく やれよ るんぱっぱ
Now do it well, run-pappa.
どうも こんにちは きみのぶんしん です
Hello there, I'm your doppelgänger.
どうもこんにちは、キミの分身です
Hello there, I'm your doppelganger.
横島な頭 囚人 はむかう ファクター
Wicked thoughts, a prisoner defying the factor,
嘘を無造作絞り 呪詛は折るような
squeezing lies casually, as if breaking curses,
夜な夜な日遊びで意識する 常時のろが溶ける頃
night after night playing with fire, conscious as the constant spell thaws.
違和感は残業してる クークーざくざくしてる
A sense of incongruity works overtime, cooing and slashing away,
たったったスコベたれて 脱線にはいろんばって
dashing along, loafing around, stepping into derailments,
健康をいじぎされた 折り込んで折り込んで
with health tampered with, folding it in over and over,
懲り懲り懲りてきにポジより願いを垂れ
utterly fed up, spilling prayers rather than positivity.
わざわざ愛を愛と呼べるならいっそ僕はフールみたい
If we dare call love "love," then I'm acting like a fool all the more.
話したいこともなくていくからそこでご臨終だと気づいたの
Having nothing left to talk about, I realized right there that it was the end.
わざわざ君を喰ってしたなら僕のアクセとはどこへやら
If I went out of my way to consume you, where on earth did my accessories go?
散れ散れ針とファンデーション 下を晒してがすぐさま埋まっているの
Scatter, needles and foundation, exposing our lowliness and instantly getting buried.
横島な頭 囚人 はむかう ファクター
Wicked thoughts, a prisoner defying the factor,
嘘を無造作絞り 呪詛は折るような
squeezing lies casually, as if breaking curses,
夜な夜な日遊びで意識する 常時のろが溶ける頃
night after night playing with fire, conscious as the constant spell thaws.
絶景焦点ビーバー おつむが軽い方に群れを上げた
A superb focal point, beaver, raising a flock toward the lighter-headed side,
手当たり次第だけど自分が持ってない
grabbing whatever's at hand, yet lacking what I truly possess,
レセプトケチ死のように歌ったか
singing as if reciting cheap receipts—
わざわざ愛を愛と呼べるならいっそ僕はフールみたい
If we dare call love "love," then I'm acting like a fool all the more.
話したいわけがなくていくから気付かないわけもないだろうな
Having no reason to want to talk, there's no way you wouldn't notice.
わざわざ君を食ってしたなら僕のアクセとはどこへやら
If I went out of my way to consume you, where on earth did my accessories go?
千切れた針とファンデーション 下を晒すだけがすぐさまれいてる
Torn needles and foundation, exposing our lowliness and instantly getting buried.
恨んで離れすったなら尻尾も泥になってたわむれて
If we resentfully drifted apart, our tails would turn to mud and play around.
わざわざ愛を愛と呼べるならいっそ僕はフールみたい
If we dare call love "love," then I'm acting like a fool all the more.
話したいこともなくていくからそこでご臨終だと気づいたの
Having nothing left to talk about, I realized right there that it was the end.
わざわざ君を食ってしたなら僕のアクセとはどこへやら
If I went out of my way to consume you, where on earth did my accessories go?
わざわざ愛を愛と呼ぶんならいっそ僕が消えるみたい
If we dare call love "love," it's as if I'll simply vanish all the more.
終わりのキスも何倍目 横島に見せかされてまるていて
How many farewell kisses is this? Flashing wicked sights, we're completely spellbound.
まるでいなさい
As if you're right here...
たけよ スタジオさみいだよ
Jeez, the studio is freezing...
ずっと...寒すぎんだよ、この、このスタジオ、カバーのスタジオは。
It's just... way too cold in this studio, Cover's studio.
え？たけよ、意味がわからない。ふざけ上がって。
Huh? Jeez, I don't get the point. Messing around with me.
たけよ、はん...
Jeez, man...
椅子がたけいし... てめえか！
The chair is... Was that you?!
てめえかよ！え、その腐った根性、笑ったね。
It was you! Heh, that rotten spirit of yours, you're laughing, huh?
その心、笑ってるね。
Deep down, you're laughing.
悪いけどね、あんたよりよっぽど生きてるんだよ！
Too bad for you, I'm living way more than you ever will!
もっと生きたいんだよ！
I want to live more!
おい！最後までちゃんみるって言って！
Hey! You said you'd watch till the end!
配信最後までちゃんみるって言って！
Say you'll watch the stream till the end!
あーーっ！
Ahhh!
僕がずっと前から思ってる事を話そうか
Shall I tell you what I've been thinking for a long time?
友達に戻れたら これ以上はもう望まないさ
If we could go back to being friends, I'd want nothing more.
君がそれでいいなら
If you're fine with that,
僕だってそれで構わないさ
I don't mind either.
嘘つきの僕が吐いた 反対言葉の愛の唄
A love song of contradictory words spoken by a liar like me.
今日は特別な日は 土砂降りの晴天でした
Today, a special day, was a torrential sunny day.
昨日もずっと暇で 一日満喫してました
Yesterday was totally boring too, and I enjoyed the whole day.
別に君のことなんて 考え てなんかいないさ
It's not like I was thinking about you or anything.
いやでも本当は 考え てたかもなんて迷子だ
No, wait, maybe I was thinking about it... I'm lost.
逃げ出すように迷路みたいに廻る
Running away, wandering like a maze,
僕の頭ん中は 潜る深さ
inside my head... diving deeper,
この両手から こぼれそうなほど君にもらった愛は
the love I received from you, enough to spill from both hands,
どこに捨てよう 限りある余裕をひらり捲くわ
where should I throw it? I flutteringly scatter my limited composure.
「もういらないよ」
"I don't need it anymore."
僕がずっと前から思ってる事を話そうか
Shall I tell you what I've been thinking for a long time?
姿は見えないのに 言葉だけ見えちゃってるんだ
Though your figure isn't visible, only your words are visible.
僕が知らないことがあるだけで気が狂いそうだ
Just knowing there are things I don't know drives me crazy.
ブラ下がった感情が 綺麗なのと汚いのか
Whether the hanging emotions are beautiful or dirty,
僕には まだわからない 捨てる宛てもないんだ
I still don't know, and I have nowhere to throw them away.
言葉の裏の裏が 見えるまで待つからさ
I'll wait until I can see the truth behind your words.
「待つクライならいんじゃないか」
"If you're going to wait, isn't that fine?"
進まない君と止まった僕の 知らない秘密を何処で埋めよう
Where shall I fill the unknown secrets between you who won't move and me who stopped?
手探りの弱虫さ
Such a groping coward.
この両手から こぼれそうなほど君にもらった愛を
The love you gave me, enough to spill from both hands,
誰に譲ろう? その二人分の手があるわけないだろ
to whom should I hand it? There's no way I have two pairs of hands for that.
「まだ、待つよ」
"I'll still wait."
「もういいか」
"Enough is enough."
まぁお話しない
Well, we won't talk.
君はすべてさ
You are everything.
be my baby
まぁお話しない
Well, we won't talk.
君はすべてさ
You are everything.
be my baby
気まぐれメルシー
[Title: Kimagure Mercy]
ほらほら また始まった
Look, look, it's started again.
お得意の自己弁護言い訳 「でもね」
Your specialty self-defense excuses, "But..."
「だって」
"Because..."
ほらほら また始まった
Look, look, it's started again.
ごめん！からのkissのパターンって感じ？安易
"Sorry!" then a kiss pattern, right? How easy.
「いつかアタシだけ」そんな夢見たこともあったけど
"Someday you'll only look at me" I even had a dream like that, but
寂しい時だけ電話して
you only call me when you're lonely.
もううんざりだわ
I'm already fed up with it!
全然アタシに興味ないじゃん
You're not interested in me at all, are you?
キミが好きなのは自分でしょう
The one you like is yourself, right?
やっぱりアタシに興味ないじゃん
As I thought, you're not interested in me.
その話もう聞き飽きたわ
I'm tired of hearing that story already.
そもそも大体アタシに興味ないじゃん
In the first place, you're generally not interested in me.
そーやってまた誤魔化して...
Doing that again, making excuses...
be my boy わがまますぎる baby
Be my boy, you're too selfish, baby.
抱きしめてね！
Hug me!
ホントキミはしょーもないな 甘いアタシ 「しょーがないな」
You're really pathetic. I act sweet, saying, "I can't help it."
泣いたって 行かないでって 言ったって 変わりゃしないよ
Even if I cry, even if I say don't go, it won't change!
もう少しだけならまぁ 踊ってもいいかもな とろけて とろけて イキたいの
If it's just a little bit more, well, maybe dancing is okay. I want to melt, melt, and go to climax.
どんなアピールも意味ないし 気づいてくれないけど
Any appeal I make is meaningless and you don't notice it, but
アタシが寂しい時だって
even when I'm lonely,
逢いにきて！
come and see me!
全然アタシに興味ないじゃん
You're not interested in me at all, are you?
どこがダメなの？教えてよ
Where is it bad? Tell me.
やっぱりアタシに興味ないじゃん
As I thought, you're not interested in me.
携帯ばかりいじってさ
Just playing with your phone.
そもそも大体アタシに興味ないじゃん
In the first place, you're generally not interested in me.
少しぐらい期待させて
Let me look forward to it a little bit.
lonely girl 独り占めしてよ baby
Lonely girl, monopolize me, baby.
振り回さないで！
Don't push me around!
ねぇ？ maybe melty? ワン・ツー shall we dance? 踊りましょう
Hey? Maybe melty? One, two, shall we dance? Let's dance.
はやく 手と手繋いで 最後にひとつだけ 溺れるくらい愛してよ
Hurry, hand in hand, just one last thing, love me until I drown.
全然アタシに興味ないじゃん
You're not interested in me at all, are you?
キミが好きなのは自分でしょう
The one you like is yourself, right?
やっぱりアタシに興味ないじゃん
As I thought, you're not interested in me.
その話もう聞き飽きたわ
I'm tired of hearing that story already.
そもそも大体アタシに興味ないじゃん
In the first place, you're generally not interested in me.
そーやってまた誤魔化して...
Doing that again, making excuses...
get the last dance 覚悟はできてるの？
Get the last dance, are you ready?
気まぐれメルシィ
Kimagure Mercy.
...おあじは いかが？
...How does it taste?
お前の苦労はずっと見ていたぞ
I've been watching your hard work all along.
本当に良く頑張ったな
You've really worked hard.
ついに我慢が報われ、膨大な富を得る
Finally, your patience is rewarded, and you gain vast wealth.
このライブを飛ばしてしまえば、これまでの苦労は全て水泡だ
If you skip this live stream, all your past efforts will come to nothing.
世界中がお前を否定しても、吾輩だけはお前を見つめてやる
Even if the whole world rejects you, only I will gaze upon you.
さんざん苦しんだのだ、もう楽になれ
You've suffered enough, now be at ease.
富を望んでいるのなら、やることがある
If you desire wealth, there is something you must do.
このライブを最後まで見て、チャンネル登録するんだ
Watch this live stream to the very end and subscribe to the channel.
やり方は簡単だ、誰にでもできる 下の赤いチャンネル登録ボタンを押して、高評価ボタンを押すのだ
The method is simple, anyone can do it. Press the red subscribe button below and hit the like button.
これで幸福の清算が始まる
With this, the settlement of happiness begins.
吾輩は決して無理強いはしない やるもやらないも、もうお前次第だ
I will never force you. Whether you do it or not is entirely up to you now.
では締めくくりに吾輩の波動を送る
Now, to conclude, I will send forth my wave.
3、2、1、今だ！
3, 2, 1, now!
お前のライブ運は上昇している このままライブを見続けるのだ
Your live stream luck is rising. Continue watching the stream just like this!
甘い夢見て 心までラ・プ・ラ・プ・ラ・プ付けづけて
Dreaming a sweet dream, staining even my heart, la-pu-la-pu-la-pu...
ただ 深い窓 ろみのどにラ・プ・ラ・プ・ラ・プ 混ざり合って
Just deep in the window's slumber, mixing together, la-pu-la-pu-la-pu...
ぐるるるる
Grurururu...
ひとつ ふたつ どこ闇にラ・プ・ラ・プ・ラ・プ とろけて
One, two, melting into the darkness somewhere, la-pu-la-pu-la-pu...
だから 熱い その 命さえラ・プ・ラ・プ・ラ・プ のまれてさ
So even that hot life is swallowed up, la-pu-la-pu-la-pu...
ぐるるるるるる
Grurururururu...
me you for you be a ufo
気付けば辺り薄暗くなる
Before I knew it, it's getting dim around.
楽しい時間すぐなくなる
Fun times pass by so quickly.
会える機会も少なくなるとするなら
If our chances to meet get fewer and fewer,
肺いっぱい吸う クラクラ
let's inhale our lungs out until we're dizzy.
ハロー イエス 皆 調子どう？
Hello, yes, how is everyone doing?
男子どう？ 女子どう？
How are the boys? How are the girls?
あっちもこっちも たちまちハマっちまう
Here and there, everyone gets hooked instantly.
まあチマチマすんな
Well, don't sweat the small stuff,
バッチこい バッチこい
bring it on, bring it on!
やけに早いな脈と鼓動
Pulse and heartbeat rushing unusually fast,
やばい心拍数 ほぼ昏倒
dangerous heart rate, almost collapsing.
敵は誰だ？ そこんとこ問う
Who is the enemy? I gotta ask,
納得いくまでとことんトーク
talking it through till we're fully satisfied.
他のみんながほっとこうと
Just when everyone else tries to leave it alone,
思いついたら速攻行動
when I think of something, I act immediately.
繋がっているから届く音
The sound reaches because we're connected.
一緒に見よう？ 心の奥
Shall we see together deep in our hearts?
まって むり しんどい
Wait, no way, this is rough.
笑ってんのに涙ドブドブでる
I'm laughing yet tears are pouring out.
感情不安定で草
Emotionally unstable, lol.
にんげんっていいな
Being human is nice, huh?
まって むり しんどい
Wait, no way, this is rough.
涙止まんなくって笑えてきたな
Tears wouldn't stop, but I started to laugh.
脈、手首、心臓
Pulse, wrists, heartbeat,
生きるの精一杯
living life to the fullest.
愛情 友情 劣情 扇情 iとu その延長線上
Love, friendship, base passion, sensationalism, on the line of "i" and "u".
一生ぶん的心臓の音
A lifetime's worth of heartbeat sound,
あと何回残っている？
how many times are left?
他の人よりも早い気がする
It feels faster than anyone else's.
レッツビギニングナウ シンキングタイム
Let's beginning now, thinking time.
暴き出すルール
Uncovering the rules.
全生命の鼓動が合計で同じ
All life's heartbeats total up the same.
ゾウさんもネズミさんもすべて同じ
Elephants and mice are all the same.
私はどう？
What about me?
ドキドキ使いすぎてしにそう
Using up my heartbeats too fast, I might die.
あの日強烈に痛かったカウンター
That day, the counter hit me with intense pain.
残り時間光ったカウントダウン
The countdown shone with remaining time.
諦めるのはなんて簡単
Giving up is so easy.
それでも闘うんだ
Even so, I'll keep fighting.
見てくれてた？ 超頑張ったよ
Were you watching? I tried my absolute best.
健やかなときも
In times of health
つらい深いときも
and in times of deep pain,
ずっとそこにいてくれてたんだねありがとう
you were always there with me, thank you.
ピコピコの高鳴りは始まりの音
The pulsing throb is the sound of the beginning.
まって むり しんどい
Wait, no way, this is rough.
笑ってんのに涙ドブドブでる
I'm laughing yet tears are pouring out.
感情不安定で草
Emotionally unstable, lol.
にんげんっていいな
Being human is nice, huh?
まって むり しんどい
Wait, no way, this is rough.
涙止まんなくって笑えてきたね
Tears wouldn't stop, but we started to laugh.
脈、手首、心臓
Pulse, wrists, heartbeat,
生きるの精一杯
living life to the fullest.
言いたかったことばかり
Just things I wanted to say,
こぼれてきた物語
stories that spilled out.
言えなかったその中に
Within the things I couldn't say,
大切なものがあったり
there were precious things.
だから愛せるうちに愛そう
So let's love while we can love,
この心臓が動く限りは
as long as this heart keeps beating.
好きだよ 超えて すきだよ
I like you, beyond that, I love you.
愛してる 超えて あいしてる
I adore you, beyond that, I cherish you.
まだまだ伝わらないな
Still doesn't quite get across.
もう まって むり しんどいな
Already, wait, no way, this is rough.
愛そう あお、いっそ
Let's love, or rather, let's
このしんどさ詰め込んで伝えよう
pack this hardship and convey it.
まって むり しんどい
Wait, no way, this is rough.
笑ってんのに涙ドブドブでる
I'm laughing yet tears are pouring out.
感情不安定で草
Emotionally unstable, lol.
にんげんっていいな
Being human is nice, huh?
まって むり しんどい
Wait, no way, this is rough.
涙止まんなくって笑えてきたね
Tears wouldn't stop, but we started to laugh.
この音 この鼓動を
This sound, this heartbeat,
恋と呼ぼうか
shall we call it love?
愛情 友情 熱情 扇情 iとu その延長線上
Love, friendship, passion, sensationalism, on the line of "i" and "u".
テレスコープ越しの感情 六日に全部詰め込んだ
Emotions through a telescope, packed entirely into six days.
踊ってない夜を知らない
I don't know a night without dancing,
踊ってない夜が君に要らない
a night without dancing you don't need.
踊ってない夜を知らない
I don't know a night without dancing,
踊ってない夜が君に要らないよ
a night without dancing you don't need.
踊ってない夜なんてもう僕は知らない
I no longer know a night without dancing.
見える？この目の涙
Can you see the tears in these eyes?
命の色に滲んでいる
Bleeding into the color of life.
何を残して与えた？
What did you leave behind and give?
問いかけて 壊れて
Calling out, collapsing.
青と赤と白 混ざるこの世界中で叫んでいる
Shouting within this world where blue, red, and white mix.
何を求めて歩いた？
What were you walking in search of?
追いかけて 疲れて
Chasing, getting tired.
どれくらい異常？
How abnormal is it?
壊れているの？
Am I breaking down?
壊れているよ
I am breaking!
それでも 息を…
Even still, breathing...
…したい、したい
...wanting to breathe.
君に見えているの？
Can you see it?
夢のように最後の言葉も詰まるよ
Like in a dream, even the final words choke up.
ERROR
遠い日のこと 優しい光が
On a distant day, a faint light
空に満ち溢れている
is flooding the sky.
何を選んで並べた？
What did you choose and line up?
涙色 重ねて
Tears' colors overlapping.
浮かぶその身体 意識の中 溶けて
That floating body melts within consciousness,
滲んでしまう
and completely blurs.
何を見てきて比べた？
What have you seen and compared it to?
悲しくて 忘れて
It's sad, I've forgotten.
どれくらい異常？
How abnormal is it?
歪んでいるの？
Is it distorted?
歪んでいるよ
It is distorted!
それでも 息を…
Even still, breathing...
…したい、したい
...wanting to breathe.
夢を見ているの
Am I dreaming?
想う君に最後の言葉も詰まるよ
Thinking of you, even the final words choke up.
ERROR
与えることも 失うことも
Even if I give, even if I lose,
忘れることも できないの？
even if I forget, can't I do it?
暴れ出す この ERROR
Running wild, this ERROR.
殺して 笑う僕が また ERROR
Killing, smiling, I am once again ERROR.
壊しているの？
Am I breaking down?
壊して知るの？
Do you know by breaking?
それでも 涙
Even still, the tears...
…イタイ、痛い
...hurt, hurt.
君に届いたの？
Have they reached you?
歌う声に最後の言葉並べてもERROR
Even lining up final words with my singing voice, ERROR.
見える? この目の涙
Can you see? Through these tears
命の色に滲んでいる
The colors of life are blurring.
何を残して与えた?
What are you leaving behind?
問いかけて 壊れて
Calling out, collapsing.
青と赤と白混ざる
Blue, red, and white blurring,
この世の中で叫んでいる
In this world I'm shouting.
壊して、いつの
Breaking, when will it...
壊して、死ぬの
Break and die?
止めても、涙
Even if I stop, tears...
痛い、痛い
Hurt, hurt.
君に届いたの?
Did it reach you?
歌う声に最後の
With my final singing voice,
言葉並べても
Even if I line up the words...
重なる色 滲んで
Overlapping colors blurring,
壊れているの?
Am I breaking down?
壊れているよ
I am breaking!
それでも息を
Even still I want to keep...
...したい したい
...Breathing, breathing.
夢を見ているの
Am I dreaming?
想う君に最後の
In thoughts of you, the last...
言葉も詰まるよ
Words are blocked.
与えることも
Even if I give,
失うことも
Even if I lose,
忘れることも
Even if I forget,
できないの?
Can't I?
暴れ出すこの エラー 殺して
I'm restless, kill this error.
笑う僕がまた ERROR
Laughing, I'm still ERROR.
壊しているの?
Am I broken?
壊して知るの
Do you know what's broken?
それでも涙 ...イタイ イタイ
Even still the tears... hurt, hurt.
君に届いたの?
Have I reached you?
歌う声に最後の
With my last singing voice,
言葉並べても
Even if I line up the words,
重なる色 滲んで
Overlapping colors are blurring.
壊れているの?
Am I breaking down?
壊れているよ
I am breaking!
それでも息を ...したい したい
Even still I want to... breathe.
君に見えてたの?
Did I just see you?
ERROR
本日は皆様、ラプラス・ダークネス生誕祭をご覧いただきありがとうございます。
Today, thank you all for watching La+ Darknesss's birthday celebration.
今回、ホロライブのゲストと一緒に歌っていないことについて一言を
Regarding not singing together with Hololive guests this time...
皆さんにはわからないでしょうね!
You guys probably don't understand!
このホロライブを! 固い! その一瞬で!
This Hololive... so stiff! In that single moment!
どうしても次の曲ゲストを呼びたくて…!
I really wanted to invite guests for the next song...!
色んな人と見たいだって! こういうコラボしてたらゲストの人数とかすごいことになってさ!
I wanted to see various people! Doing collabs like this makes the guest count crazy!
他のゲストが呼べなくなったんです! うわーーーん!
We couldn't invite other guests! Waaaah!
というわけで、次の曲のゲストすごい です。
And so, the guest for the next song is amazing.
超天変地異みたいな狂騒にも慣れて
I've gotten used to all the cataclysmic rivalry.
こんな日常を平和で見間違える
Sometimes I mistake these days for peace.
ランブリング コースター 揺さぶられながら
As I'm tossed about on this roller coaster,
見失えないものはなんだ?
What is it that I can't afford to lose?
予定調和原理主義の概念に飲み込まれて
Swallowed by predictable fundamentalism,
心までがまるでおエトセトラ
Even my heart feels like "etcetera."
大嫌い 大好き
"I really hate it," "I love it,"
ちゃんと喋らなきゃ
I've got to say it clearly,
人形とさして変わらないし
Or it's no different from a doll.
宵街を往く人ばかりは
The people walking down the evening streets
嬉しそうだったり 寂しそうだったり
Seem happy, or perhaps a bit lonely.
コントラストが五線譜を飛び回り
Contrasts dance across the musical staff,
歌とリズムになる
Turning into song and rhythm.
ママレードにシュガーソング ピーナッツ&ビーターステップ
Marmalade and a sugar song, peanuts & bitter step,
甘くて苦くて目が回りそうです
Sweet and bitter, my head is spinning.
南南西を目指してパーティを続けよう
Aiming south-southwest, let's keep the party going,
世界中を驚かせてしまう夜になる
Turning this into a night that shocks the world.
I feel 上々 連鎖になってリフレクト
I feel uplifted, chaining into reflection.
アイテム ジョージ 繊細なテリフレット
Item, george, delicate reflection...
祭囃子のその上で
Right after the festival music ends,
高ぶったままの人 泣き出してしまう人
People still hyped, people bursting into tears,
大体同じだろう でも言葉にするようななら
They're probably all the same, but putting it into words
拙劣が極まり
Only highlights the clumsiness.
最高だってシュガーソング 幸せってビーターステップ
It's the best, sugar song, happiness, bitter step.
超天変地異みたいな狂騒にも慣れて
Used to the craziness like a super upheaval,
こんな日常を平和と見間違う
mistaking this everyday life for peace.
Rambling coaster 揺さぶられながら 見失えないものは何だ？
Rambling coaster, being shaken, what can't be lost?
平等主義原理原則の概念に飲まれて
Swallowed by egalitarian principles and rules,
心までがまるでエトセトラ
even the heart is just like an et cetera.
大嫌い 大好き ちゃんと語らなくちゃ
I hate you, I love you, gotta speak it clearly,
人形とさして変わらないし
or I'm no different from a doll.
宵街を往く人ばかりは
The crowds walking the evening streets,
嬉しそうだったり寂しそうだったり
some looking happy, some looking lonely.
コントラストが五線譜を飛び回り
Contrasts leap around the staff,
歌とリズムになる
becoming song and rhythm.
ママレードにシュガーソング ピーナッツ＆ビターステップ
Marmalade & sugar song, peanuts & bitter step,
甘くて苦くて目が回りそうです
sweet and bitter, it's making me dizzy.
南南西を目指してパーティを続けよう
Head south-southwest and keep the party going,
世界中を驚かせてしまう夜になる
a night that will astonish the world.
祭囃子のその上で 高ぶったままの人
Atop the festival music, those who remain hyped,
泣き出してしまう人 多分同じだろう
those who burst into tears, they're probably the same.
でも言葉にしようものなら
But if you try to put it into words,
拙さが極まり
the clumsiness peaks.
最高だってシュガーソング 幸せってビターステップ
The best is a sugar song, happiness is a bitter step,
死なない理由をそこに映し出せ
reflect the reason not to die right there.
惜しかったって等速度で明日はきちゃうけど
Tomorrow comes at constant speed despite regrets,
脳内天気予報のアップデートを果たしたなら
if you've updated your brain's weather forecast,
Someday 狂騒が息を潜めても
Someday, even if madness holds its breath,
Someday 正論に意味がなくなっても
Someday, even if right arguments lose meaning,
フィーリングソング＆ステップ鳴らし続けることが
keeping the feeling song & step ringing
僕たちを僕たちたらしめる証明になる
will be the proof that makes us who we are.
QED!
ママレードにシュガーソング ピーナッツ＆ビターステップ
Marmalade & sugar song, peanuts & bitter step,
世界中を驚かせ続けよう
let's keep astonishing the whole world.
北北西は後方へ その距離がおかしらしい
North-northeast is behind, that distance seems funny.
世界中を驚かせてしまう夜になる
It'll be a night that astonishes the world.
I feel 上々 連鎖になってリフレクション
I feel great, turning into a chain reflection.
甘くて苦くて目が回りそうです
Sweet and bitter, it's making me dizzy.
南南西を目指してパーティを続けよう
Let's head south-southwest and keep the party going.
世界中を驚かせてしまう夜になる
It'll be a night that astonishes the world.
I feel 上々 連鎖になってリフレクション
I feel great, turning into a chain reflection.
Goes on 一興去って一難去ってまた一興！
Goes on, one fun thing passes, one hardship passes!
Goes on 一難去ってまた一興！
Goes on, one hardship passes, then another fun thing!
え、ラプラス・ダークネスってオリ曲3曲しかないの？
Huh, La+ Darknesss only has three original songs?
やっぱ期待しちゃだめじゃない、新曲なんて出すわけないんだから
Well, you shouldn't get your hopes up, there's no way she'd release a new song.
ラプラス・ダークネスなんて当てにしちゃダメよ
You shouldn't rely on La+ Darknesss.
え、新曲出るの？ しかもDECO*27さんなの！？
Wait, a new song is coming out? And it's by DECO*27!?
タイトル？「バグラブ」？
Title? "Bug Love"?
それって…つまり自己防衛？
That... means self-defense?
この後披露するの？
Is she going to perform it after this?
これ見ないとだめじゃない？
We gotta watch it, right?
この後見逃しちゃダメよ
Don't miss it after this.
つまり自己防衛？
Meaning self-defense?
やっぱりラブレースハッピーじゃん
After all, it's Love-less happy, right?
あーまさか これってまさか好きってやつか
Ah, no way, could this possibly be what they call love?
どんなんか知らないけど はってなって火花バチってなるの
I don't know what it's like, but sparks fly and go 'huh'!
鈍感でいられたらなあ
I wish I could have remained oblivious...
あーこんなはずじゃ とんだ恥じゃ 残念の始まりじゃ
Ah, this shouldn't be! Such an embarrassment, the start of regrets!
あーとんでも事変 ハートの治安 曖昧でおしまいじゃ
Ah, an incredible incident, heart's security ending in ambiguity!
気になって気にしないとこ気になるとこ
Caring about what I shouldn't care about, things that bug me,
気まぐれって気に病むじゃない
being capricious, doesn't it weigh on your mind?
バグってるラブ あたしなんですか？ やだよがっかりラブレース デビュー ベイビーじゃん
Is bugged love me? No way, what a disappointing love-less debut baby!
痛いだけの気持ち 最悪の見込み 好きって認めないね
Feelings that just hurt, worst-case outlook, refusing to admit I'm in love.
バグってるラブ あたしなんかじゃない そうだやっぱりラブレースハッピーじゃん
Bugged love isn't about me at all—wait, it really is a love-less happy!
期待なんてナシナ あっちいけバリア 好きってならないでね
No expectations, go away barrier, don't let it become love!
の距離感です
That's our sense of distance.
正直あたしは終わった
Honestly, I'm done for.
何しようなどうもモヤモヤが消えない
No matter what I do, this haziness won't disappear.
呆然ただ笑った いつも通りロンリー
Dumbfounded, I just laughed, lonely as always.
息をしたいのに
Even though I just want to breathe...
意地張っていじけるとかいじらしいから 恋って異常なんじゃない？
Acting stubborn and sulking is endearing, isn't love abnormal?
da da la la da la dark
ra pa pan pan pan
you will want it more , want it more
You will want it more, want it more
ra pa pan pan pan
風穴開けたんだって
I've blown a hole through it,
支配は始まった
domination has begun.
息はもう掛けたの
I've already breathed my spell,
but you don't know
自覚ないはずよ
You shouldn't even be aware of it.
抑え切れない自力制御不能なpower
Uncontainable, uncontrollable power!
捕まえてみろよ 影形もない my heart
Try and catch my heart, which has no shadow!
i 'm so crazy crazy in love
I'm so crazy, crazy in love!
半信半疑な素振りは no no 心に従って
Doubtful gestures are a no-no, follow your heart.
忠誠心見せてよ 今こそ
Show me your loyalty, right now!
baby don't let me down
ra pa pan pan pan
gotta be kidding me クセになるでしょ？
Gotta be kidding me, it's addictive, right?
ra pa pan pan pan
no love 's killing me 足りないのよ
No love's killing me, it's not enough!
oh no . . .
Oh no...
yes ！ dark breath
Yes! Dark breath.
感じるでしょ 革命的存在を
You can feel it, a revolutionary existence,
it 's god 's breath
it's god's breath.
鬱屈感情 吹き払って
Blow away all these gloomy feelings!
ra pa pan pan pan
浅はかな言葉 建前並べて
Lining up shallow words and polite pretenses,
何も無いことぐらい baby i know
as if nothing's wrong, baby I know.
ほら 図星でしょ？
See? Hit the nail on the head, right?
枯れゆくこと受け入れた鮮やかな flower
A vibrant flower that accepts its own withering,
知りながら贈る笑顔に潜む姿
hiding behind a smile given knowingly.
心侵食される前に その身を預けて
Before your heart is invaded, surrender yourself,
目覚めさせるのよ 永遠に
and awaken it, for eternity.
i never let you down
ra pa pan pan pan
gotta be kidding me クセになるでしょ？
Gotta be kidding me, it's addictive, right?
ra pa pan pan pan
no love 's killing me 足りないのよ
No love's killing me, it's not enough!
oh no . . .
Oh no...
yes ！ dark breath
Yes! Dark breath.
感じるでしょ 運命的衝動を
You can feel it, a fateful impulse,
it 's god 's breath
it's god's breath.
脳内細胞 酔わせて
Intoxicating every cell in the brain!
ra pa pan pan pan
時代 未来 なら 見い出す
If it's era or future, I'll find it out.
意外じゃない i 'm a genius
It's no surprise, I'm a genius!
全知全能 like a jesus
Omniscient and omnipotent like a Jesus,
巻き起こす
stirring it all up!
待ち侘びてたんだ
I've been waiting for this,
導くの全て i 'm sorry
guiding everything, I'm sorry.
誰もが羨む桃源郷へと i 'll change it
I'll change it into a utopia everyone envies.
天才の常套手段は きっと 凡才には special ね
A genius's cliché is surely special to ordinary folks.
誰にも気付かれないけれど 手に入れるわ
Even if no one notices, I will make it mine!
ra pa pan pan pan
gotta be kidding me クセになるでしょ？
Gotta be kidding me, it's addictive, right?
ra pa pan pan pan
no love 's killing me 足りないのよ
No love's killing me, it's not enough!
oh no . . .
Oh no...
yes ！ dark breath
Yes! Dark breath.
感じるでしょ 普通じゃない 相当
You can feel it, it's far from ordinary, quite a lot,
it 's god 's breath
it's god's breath.
第六感をお澄ませて
Purify your sixth sense!
ra pa pan pan pan
はい、披露でしたー！
There you have it, my performance!
どうだった？
How was it?
え、よく分からない？
Huh? You don't really get it?
しょうがないな、もう。
Well, can't be helped.
じゃあ、詳細を教えてあげましょう。
Then let me give you the details.
こちら！ じゃん！
Right here! Ta-da!
ラプラス・ダークネス誕生日記念2025！
La+ Darknesss Birthday Commemoration 2025!
え、フルセットこんな感じです。
Yep, this is what the full set looks like.
それでは、1つずつ内容を見ていきましょう。
Now, let's look at the contents one by one.
まずはこちら！ じゃん！
First is this! Ta-da!
Tシャツだね。
It's a T-shirt.
ラインだよ、これが、っていうことでね。
"LINE da yo, kore ga", so yeah.
生誕、生誕に！
Birthday, for the birthday!
これ、どんな感じだ？
What's this like?
しゃべっ...
It talks—
え？しゃべっ、え？
Huh? It talks? Huh?
しゃべっ...
It talk—
え？
Huh?
しゃべっ...
It talk—
ラプラスさんのグッズで今回Tシャツが出るそうなんですが
I heard T-shirts are coming out as merch, but...
まことに遺憾です。
It is truly regrettable.
残念です。
It's unfortunate.
いいTシャツ来てんじゃんかよ、ぷるるだろ、それ。
You're wearing a nice T-shirt! That's Pururu, right?
バキバキラブ様です。
It's Bakibaki Lap-sama.
ラプラスさんの生誕グッズがカラスのニット帽らしいんですが
I heard La+'s birthday merch includes a crow knit cap...
世界的なアイドルですもんね、乗るしかない、このビッグウェーブに。
She's a global idol, after all. Gotta ride this big wave!
はい、披露目でしたー！
There you have it, the unveiling!
どうだった？
How was it?
え、よく分からない？
Huh? You don't really get it?
しょうがないな、もう。
Well, can't be helped, I suppose.
じゃあ、詳細を教えてあげましょう。
Then let me give you the details.
こちら！ じゃん！ ラプラス・ダークネス誕生日記念2025フルセットこんな感じです。
Here's the La+ Darknesss Birthday Commemoration 2025 full set.
それでは、1つずつ内容を見ていきましょう。まずはこちら！
Now, let's look at the contents one by one. First is this!
じゃん！ Tシャツだね。
Ta-da! It's a T-shirt.
ラインだよ、これが、っていうことでね。イラストが入ったTシャツだよ。
"LINE da yo, kore ga", so yeah. It's a T-shirt with art on it.
え、このねイラストはね、ちょぼらうにょぽみ先生が描いてくれたよ。
This illustration was drawn by Choboraunyopomi-sensei!
ええた！かわいいでしょ？いっぱいきてね、なんかTシャツのグッズのほうも出してるんですけどね。
Yay! Isn't it cute? Wear it a lot! We also have T-shirt merch out.
幾つあっても困りませんからね。いっぱい着てください。
You can never have too many, so please wear them a lot!
そして続いては、こちら！
And next is this!
ボイスキーホルダー私服衣装ver.ということででですね、
The voice keychain, casual outfit ver....
去年も思ったりめちゃくちゃ大人気だった我が家のボイスキーホルダーで、
It's our household's voice keychain that was surprisingly super popular last year,
もうみんな、また売って、また売ってって言われたから、
and everyone kept asking me to sell it again and again,
え、しょうがないなと思ってまた出すことにしました。
so I figured I had no choice and decided to release it again.
いろこしん？い、いろこりゅ、ちょいろこせんせいじゃなくて、
Iroko-shin? I- Irokoryu, not Choy Iroko-sensei...
イラストは、イラスト今回もシロコ先生に描いてもらったよ、まって！描いた！
The illustration, this time too, Shiroko-sensei drew it for me—wait, drawn!
はい、どんなボイスが入ってるかお楽しみに。お次は、こちら！
Yes, look forward to what kind of voices are included. Next is this!
カラスニット帽！
The crow knit hat!
てことてで、我が家にいつも着飾っているカラスの、え、モチーフが入った、顔か、顔が入ったニット帽です。
So, it's a knit hat featuring the motif and face of the crow that always hangs around our house.
はい、これ目隠し帽になるんですけど、ここ目だけ出てるやつ。
Yes, this becomes a blindfold hat, but only the eyes stick out here.
え、これはちょっとイベントとかにつけていくと、保安上危険なんで、
If you wear this to events, it's a security hazard,
え、イベントに行くときは顔出しで家につけるときはこの目隠し帽でつけてね。温かいよ。
so when going to events show your face, and when wearing it at home use this blindfold hat, okay? It's warm.
そしてフルセット購入特典は、こちら！
And the full set purchase bonus is this!
直筆メッセージ&箔押し複製サイン入りポストカード、ちょぽらうにょぽみ先生の描き下ろしポストカードです。
A postcard with a handwritten message and hot-stamped replica signature, illustrated specially by Choporau Nyopomi-sensei.
なんと今回は数量限定じゃないです！頑張っていっぱい書きます！
And amazingly, this time it's not limited in quantity! I'll do my best and sign a ton!
さようなら我が家のおててて、そしてさらにフルセットを購入した方には、
Goodbye, our house's hands... And furthermore, for those who purchased the full set,
ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームで使用できるカードが1枚ついてくるよ。
one card that can be used in the Hololive Official Card Game will come with it.
じゃん、同梱するカードはホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップでご購入されたお客様のみ対象となります。
Ta-da, the included card is only available to customers who purchased at the Hololive Production Official Shop.
えっとね、特典につくのはゲームで1枚デッキ使用できて推しホロメンをアピールできるキーカード推しホロメンカードです。カードの詳細とか遊び方についてはホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームの公式ホームページで確認してください。
Um, the bonus is an Oshi Hololmember card, a key card that can be used once in a deck during the game to showcase your Oshi Hololmember. Please check the Hololive Official Card Game official website for card details and how to play.
え、このカードは日本語版のみとなりますのでご留意ください。
Please note that this card is available in Japanese only.
そして我が家が居るキュリオスユニバースも6月20日来月、発売されるので一緒に使ってね。
And our house's Curiosity Universe will also be released next month on June 20th, so please use them together.
はい、ということでグッズもよろしく。
Alright, so please check out the merch as well.
いや、今回はねゲストがもりだくさんだったね。
Man, this time there were so many guests.
えっといろんな振り返りとかはまた配信で話すかもしれないからそのときお楽しみに。
Um, I might talk about various lookbacks on stream again, so look forward to that.
ばいばい！ばいばいばいばい！
Bye-bye! Bye-bye-bye-bye!